David E. Schindel Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
David E. Schindel Archives
1958-1972
IPAR.001094
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
5
The archives of David E. Schindel including maps, specimen information, and his dissertation.
Schindel, David Edward
Biographical Sketch
Dr. Schindel is an invertebrate paleontologist whose research explored evolutionary theory, computer-based analysis of evolutionary change, and the role of the fossil record in shaping evolutionary theory. He received a B.S. in Geology from the University of Michigan (1973) and went on to study marine geology briefly at the University of Southern California. From 1974 to 1977 he was a doctoral student at Harvard University and an advisee of Dr. Stephen J. Gould. Dr. Schindel was a Pre-Doctoral Fellow in Systematic and Evolutionary Biology at the Smithsonian from 1977-1978 and was awarded a Ph.D. in Geological Sciences from Harvard in 1979. Dr. Schindel joined the Yale University faculty in 1978 in the Department of Geology and Geophysics. He served as an Assistant and Associate Professor and the Curator of Invertebrate Fossils in the Yale Peabody Museum from 1978 to 1986. In 1986 he joined the National Science Foundation.
Description of the Material
Consists primarily of topographic and county maps of west Texas. Also includes some dissertation material.
New York; Connecticut; USA; Texas; Maps; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Maps, 1958-1972; Series I
  - 1958-1960., 001097
    - County map. Callahan Co. (1: 125000). Texas General Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1960; 002354
    - County map. Shackelford Co. (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1960; 002362
    - Topographic map. Palo Pinto,TX 15 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey, 1958; 002350
    - Topographic map. Gordon,TX 15 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey, 1959; 002339
    - Topographic map. Mineral Wells,TX 15 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey, 1959; 002348
    - Topographic map. Jacksboro,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1960; 002345
  - 1961-1963., 001098
    - County map. Erath Co. (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1963; 002357
    - County map. Hood Co. & Somervell Co. (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1963; 002358
    - County map. Jack Co. (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1963; 002359
    - County map. Palo Pinto Co. (1: 125000). Texas General Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department. Annotated with localities., 1963; 002360
    - County map. Parker Co. (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1963; 002361
    - County map. West Co. (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1963; 002364
    - County map. Young Co. (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1963; 002365
    - Topographic map. Mineral City, OH 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1961; 002330
    - Topographic map. Sugarcreek, OH 7.5 Quad. (1: 24,000) USGS topographic, 1961; 002333
  - 1964-1963., 001099
    - County map. Brown Co (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1964; 002353
    - County map. Coleman Co. (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1964; 002355
    - County map. Eastland Co. (1: 125000). Texas Grneral Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1964; 002356
  - 1967-1969., 001100
    - Topographic map. Brad,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002334
    - Topographic map. Caddo, TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002335
    - Topographic map. Caddo NE,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002336
    - Topographic map. Cove Creek,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002337
    - Topographic map. Eliasville,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002338
    - Topographic map. Graham,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002340
    - Topographic map. Grand Lake,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002341
    - Topographic map. Harpersville,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002342
    - Topographic map. Ivan North,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002343
    - Topographic map. Ivan South,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002344
    - Topographic map. La Casa,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002346
    - Topographic map. Necessity,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 2400). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002349
    - Topographic map. South Bend,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002351
    - Topographic map. Wayland,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1967; 002352
    - Topographic map. Lake Brownwood,TX 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey, 1969; 002347
  - 1970-1972., 001101
    - County map. Stephens Co. (1: 125000). Texas General Highway Map, Texas State Highway Department., 1971; 002363
  - Not Dated., 001102
    - Topographic map. Navarre, OH 15 Quad. (1: 62500) USGS Topographic, 002331
    - Topographic map. Dover, OH 7.5 Quad. (1: 24,000) USGS Topographic, 002332
- Miscellaneous, Series II
  Scope and Contents
  Miscellaneous archives including specimen information and copies of his dissertaion.
  - Dissertation Documents., 001103
    - Locality information. locality information for Harvard dissertation; Pennsylvanian of Texas, 000900
  - Specimen Information., 001104
    - Miscellaneous. Measurements of Glabrocingulum: Texas., 1982; 000199